Finding Aid for Michigan Public Media (University of Michigan) records, 2008-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Out of the Blue
  - Season 3
    - Episode 01, 2010-2011
      - Feature 1: Coordinator of Screenwriting at U-M Jim Burnstein played an integral role in advising the government of Michigan to create tax incentives to lure feature film production to the state. The deluge of films coming to Michigan has created countless opportunities-enticing the young, creative class to stay put.
      - Feature 2: A student based initiative started in Cultivating Communities recruits students to get their hands dirty. Not only operating gardens across the university campus, Cultivating Communities engages with middle and high school students in Detroit and Ann Arbor to improve their diets., 2004
      - Feature 3: Assistant Professor of Chemistry Kevin Kubarych works to unlock the complexity of molecules in a chemical transformation-holding great promise for developers of a wide range of new technologies
    - Episode 02
      - Feature 1: Facing the possible extinction of spoken Ojibwe, Lecturers in the Native American Studies Program are engaging students in the preservation of the language and community members in the revitalization of the culture.
      - Feature 2: A group of faculty at the U-M Ross School of Business lead MBA students and business leaders through an examination of organizational excellence, with an eye toward achieving transformational change.
      - Feature 3: Many Stroke victims and adults with Cerebral Palsy have limited access to physical and occupational therapy. Project ULTrA (Upper Limb Training in Adults with Hemiplegic Cerebral Palsy) now provides home based programs for patients to engage in therapy under the watchful eye of U-M based trainers.
    - Episode 03
      - Feature 1: A confluence of arts and politics in early Ann Arbor resulted in a thought revolution with far reaching influence. A group of composers from the University of Michigan School of Music were at the forefront of this creative explosion., 1960s
      - Feature 2: Beginning with its bold, and ultimately correct prediction for economic growth back in the RSQE has provided rigorous economic analysis,and each year invites leading economists to U-M to dissect and discuss the world's economy., 1952
      - Feature 3: Filling a void to gather much needed data on flowing streams of plasma from the sun, a multi-disciplinary group of students design and build a satellite to launch into orbit
    - Episode 04
      - Feature 1: A group of Masters students from multiple disciplines converge in this course at the Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy to combine academics with practical, in-the-field experiences, in this case, working with Michigan's Lenawee County to identify best practices toward streamlining local governments.
      - Feature 2: In the inaugural year of this competition to accelerate the creation of businesses in the state of Michigan, University of Michigan student teams compete with teams from universities and colleges across the state seeking prize money to launch their dream.
      - Feature 3: 45 years ago, U-M Surgeon Dr. Robert Bartlett was disturbed by the 50 percent mortality rate of children who had undergone complex heart surgery. He developed the ECMO machine which has saved thousands of lives and is now in use in intensive care units around the world.
    - Episode 05
      - Feature 1: How can professors stay informed and prepared to integrate new instructional technology in teaching? Or learn to deal with myriad issues in multicultural environments? Luckily, CRLT provides a wide range of services promoting best practices in education, often in entertaining fashion.
      - Feature 2: Since its building opened in the Life Sciences Institute has pioneered new discoveries about a whole range of diseases, including cancer, diabetes and alzheimer's. With the help of the new Innovation Partnership, promising science is moving more quickly toward life-saving drugs in the marketplace., 2003
      - Feature 3: For half a century the Alumni Association camp in northern Michigan has kept U-M families connected. One challenge the camp must constantly address is maintaining a balance between tradition and innovation.
    - Episode 06
      - Feature 1: When Presidential Candidate John F. Kennedy stopped briefly at the University of Michigan in neither he nor the throngs of students gathered to listen to him could have known that the Peace Corps would arise from their encounter., 1960
      - Feature 2: While studying dust storms in the desert of Arizona, Professor Nilton Renno discovered that the dust particles accumulate electric charges-leading to valuable information for NASA's Mars mission and the launch of a business venture offering new technologies to protect electronics from dust damage.
      - Feature 3: Preserving the history of the state, as well as that of the University of Michigan, the Bentley Historical Library provides researchers and the public with a connection to the past
    - Episode 07
      - Feature 1: With ever expanding innovations coming from its faculty and researchers, the University of Michigan launched the Venture Accelerator to speed the transition of promising new technologies into the marketplace, benefiting both the local and national economies
      - Feature 2: Seeking to gain knowledge about and promote understanding among various religious and non-religious groups, a group of University of Michigan students engage with the community beyond the University-as evidenced by their Alternative Spring Break
      - Feature 3: A young person coming from a life in foster care to a fast paced university environment faces significant challenges. Partnering with a dedicated alumnus, the university seeks to ease this transition
    - Episode 08
      - Feature 1: A team of graduate students at the School of Natural Resources and Environment study, analyze and assess multiple possibilities for greater energy efficiency at a local brewpub whose owners embrace and implement the greening of their facility
      - Feature 2: Breaking new ground with its most recent building, U-M has created a breathtaking, living-learning environment where students and faculty intermingle in a harmonious blend of design, technology and ergonomics
      - Feature 3: Restoring and conserving archival books and documents for over 60 years at U-M, Jim Craven is as much a treasure as the historical antiquities that he lovingly reconstructs, extending their 'lives' for several hundred years more
    - Episode 09
      - Feature 1: Researchers at the Institute for Social Research utilize fMRI technology to observe brain activity, leading to startling discoveries on predicting human behavior with greater accuracy than humans themselves can predict.
      - Feature 2: Faced with an array of inner city projects that fall flat due to inadequately trained community leaders and volunteers, one major foundation partners with the U-M School of Social Work seeking to break the cycle of failure and cynicism, and provide the resources for success.
      - Feature 3: With its belief in Action Based Learning as the key for preparing MBA students for the rapid pace of change in the world of business, U-M's Ross School of Business launches student teams around the globe to tackle intensive projects in a wide array of business sectors
    - Episode 10
      - Feature 1: Faculty, researchers and students from the U-M School of Natural Resources and Environment work to strengthen the vitality of the Great Lakes ecosystem as key collaborators in the Michigan Sea Grant. One component: measuring the health of the waters by close observation of Lake Sturgeon.
      - Feature 2: As a Detroit community endeavors to plan ahead and re-define itself, U-M undergraduate students in urban planning work to conduct research on the area-providing valuable data to chart a sustainable future.
      - Feature 3: With its mission to engender environmental enjoyment, stewardship and sustainability, Matthaei Botanical Gardens and Nichols Arboretum has worked for over 100 years to create educational opportunities, conduct research, and provide intimate interaction with the natural world
    - Episode 11
      - Feature 1: Students and faculty of the U-M Symphony Band travel to China for a once in a lifetime tour of this historic and dynamic country. In between performances at multiple venues, the group engages in cultural exchange with their new friends, establishing ties and building camaraderie with their generous hosts.
      - Feature 2: With the historic Carillon bells of Burton Tower undergoing a complete restoration to their original form, U-M honors a tradition that has set the tone for the campus for 80 years, making possible its continuance long into the future.
      - Feature 3: Researchers at the Lurie Nanofabrication Facility at U-M are making extraordinary advancements in manufacturing with Micro Electro Mechanical Systems (MEMS) technology, with promising new developments in a range of medical and other areas
    - Episode 12
      - Feature 1: Providing a unique opportunity for a diverse group of high school students, the ArcStart program engages these youth in a 3-week summer program to expose them to a college architecture studio as well as life at the university.
      - Feature 2: Addressing basic needs of an often neglected group of individuals, the Department of Family Medicine contributes to their medical well being while an ESL class attends to their desire to engage with the public in English.
      - Feature 3: Building on its history of providing dental services to migrant and low income individuals and families, the School of Dentistry reaches out across the state while simultaneously strengthening the skills of its students
- Archived Websites
  The Archived Website series contains archived versions of various websites associated with Michigan Public Media. These preserved websites help to document the policies and operations of the unit and offer the researcher both administrative information as well as news and informational productions. The archived websites include the home pages for the Michigan Channel, Michigan Radio, and the Out of the Blue program. Also included is the homepage for "Muslims in Michigan," an award-winning series produced by Michigan Radio in conjunction with the U-M Center for Middle Eastern and North African Studies. Archival versions of these websites (while they remain active) will be captured on a regular and ongoing basis and may be accessed via the University of Michigan Web Archives at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Archived Out of the Blue: The Michigan Difference home page, 2010-2011
  - Archived Michigan Channel home page, 2010-[ONGOING]
  - Archived Michigan Radio home page, 2010-[ONGOING]
  - Archived Muslims in Michigan home page, 2011
    (Michigan Radio series)
Index to Out to the Blue Participants
The following index lists individuals who appeared in episodes of Out of the Blue. The index is arranged by season (broadcast year) and episode. It includes University of Michigan faculty, staff and students and outside guests.
Season One Episode 01 Campbell, Myron Gingerich, Philip Muraskzko, Karin Rabuck, Carol Episode 02 Ball, Deborah Lalendran, Ashwin Sparling, Peter Episode 03 Longone, Dan Longone, Jan Slavin, Ruth Parsons, Michael Stewart, James Weinzweig, Ari Episode 04 Bernitsas, Michael Harris, Amy Oey, Sally Wagner, Brent Episode 05 Mitsak, Annie Samorezov, Julie Sayer, Jim Episode 06 Etkin, Stephanie Moriarity, Brendan Moss, Thylias Tucker, Mark Episode 07 Feldman, Eva Gelderloos, Orin Hilden, Jakob Kirchner, Jessie Morrison, Sean Montejo, Andres Episode 08 Dailey, Ian Kinnunen, Paivo O'Grady, Shawn Sinha, Siddarth Tobier, Nick Episode 09 Andreatta, Pamela Colosimo, Kristine Ann Doering, Charlie Hofer, Erik Maslowski, Eric Sharrief, Sultan Shimi, Woojin Wali, Rajat Wrobel, Clare Episode 10 Bacon, John Beam, Kathryn Beauchamp, Andrea Delbanco, Nicholas Gott, Sue Gross, Samuel Kasdan, Lawrence Levine, Zoe Li, Xu McCormack, Bridget Miller, Arthur Moran, David Season Two Episode 01 Nadelhoffer, Knute Crumsey, Jasmine Ulrich, Dale Meadows, Guy Episode 02 Herbert, Sharon Gazda, Elaine Soloway, Elliot Bornhorst, Jason Episode 03 Smith, Carl Eisendrath, Charles Gagos, Traino Episode 04 Dewar, Margaret Duweke, Eric Klionski, Dan Essl, Georg Episode 05 Alexander, Terry Verge, Bill Allen, Erin Mabry, Deanna Gott, Sue Weiss, Janet Kolevar, Kris Kennedy, Tim Rife, Dan Beall, Libby Campos, Susan Artley, Tracy Episode 06 Fischer, Ken Kondziolka, Michael Rice, Claire Ball, Deborah Lampert, Magdalene Ghousseini, Hala Yim, Jennifer Episode 07 Snodgrass, Ken Murabito, Jeanne Tobin, James Biron, Bethany Newman, Dan White, Allie Smilovitz, Jacob Kuo, Art Episode 08 Weinert, Daryl Noble, Brian Klinke, Amy Samson, Perry Washabaugh, Peter Episode 09 Ayyash, Marya Mallette, Karla Charney, Tamar Guerra, Jennifer Hulett, Sarah Blomquist, Amber Hagen, Gottfried Cornwell, Bettina Naveira, Ariadna Li, Victor Li, Mo Sakulich, Aaron Episode 10 Alexander, Buzz Paul, Jamie Episode 11 Bregman, Joel Wight, Karen Lindnor, Rudi Seitzer, Patrick Kinner, Thomas Porter, Tom Murillo, Gloria Maria Kleinman, Enriqueta Sanchez, Fernando Pyreddy, Ramu Episode 12 Strecher, Vic Considine, Shannon Warner, Kenneth Badgley, Catherine Rothstein, Mark Sickler, Brett Episode 13 Davis, Cinda-Sue Saville, Jamie Nesbit, Ken Glick, Gary Rasor, Robin Gumucio, Deborah Edwards, Chris Episode 14 Ni, Jun Daida, Jason Stein, Jeff Boulton, Matthew Montgomery, Jo Lyn Coleman, Mary Sue Ma, Madame Episode 15 Mendeloff, Kate Gray, Carol Pickrel, April Monts, Lester Collins, William Prevo, Amy Turner, Michael Jackson, Helki Tobin, James Season Three Episode 01 Burnstein, Jim Doyle, Lee Mortell, Catriona Kubarych, Kevin Baiz, Carlos Episode 02 Norri, Margaret Kimewon, Howard Quinn, Robert Spreitzer, Gretchen Wooten, Lynn Brown, Susan Hurvitz, Edward Episode 03 Daugherty, Michael Clague, Mark Fulton, George Cutler, Jamie Episode 04 Gerber, Elisabeth Bartlett, Robert Hirschl, Ronald Annich, Gail Episode 05 Cook, Connie Kaplan, Matthew Steiger, Jeffrey Saltiel, Alan Smith, Janet Gestwicki, Jason Rosenwasser, Mitch Schumacher, Hazen Episode 06 Clifford, Kay Greisberger, John Renno, Nilton Musko, Stephen B. Blouin, Francis Coombs, Leonard Jania, Karen Episode 07 Coleman, Mary Sue Nesbitt, Ken O'Connell, Jim Hartmann, Dave Kopelman, Raoul Yerkey, Rachel Galura, Joe Naasko, Rachel Harper, E. Royster Episode 08 Diamond, Jarrett Shoberg, Inga McDonald, Terrence Yim, Jennifer Johnson, Laura Mackie-Mason, Jeffrey Craven, Jim Flowers, Ann Episode 09 Falk, Emily Heusmann, Rowell Carp, Joshua Egnatios, Edward S. Miller, Pat Gant, Larry Salinas, Maria Brown, Nicole Dockery, Patricia Colbert, Calvin Bare, Rebecca Anderson, Gene O'Leary, Ted Dittmar, Amy Episode 10 LaPorte, Elizabeth Diana, Jim Chiotti, Justin Larsen, Larissa Cervenak, Thomas Grese, Bob Episode 11 Haithcock, Michael Ball, Steven Harris, James E. Wise, Kensall D. Episode 12 McMorrough, John Armstrong, Mashawnta Rodgers, Phil Peck, Dan Lee, Joanna Peggs, James Rodriquez, Mabel Piskorowski, Bill Bagramian, Robert